<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Milone A. P. on Giacomo Cordoni</title>
    <link>https://www.giacomocordoni.me/authors/milone-a.-p./</link>
    <description>Recent content in Milone A. P. on Giacomo Cordoni</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.giacomocordoni.me/authors/milone-a.-p./index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Galaxy&#39;s halo and very metal weak thick disk with SkyMapper and Gaia DR2</title>
      <link>https://www.giacomocordoni.me/publication/paper17/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.giacomocordoni.me/publication/paper17/</guid>
      <description>Galactic archeology with the dynamics of Extremely Metal-Poor stras from the &lt;em&gt;SkyMapper survey for Extremely Metal-Poor stars&lt;/em&gt;. and astrometry from Gaia DR2 to investigate the kinematics of a sample of 475 stars with a metallicity range of  -6.5&amp;lt;=[Fe/H]&amp;lt;=-2.05 dex. Exploiting the action map, we identify 16 and 40 stars dynamically consistent with the &lt;em&gt;Gaia Sausage&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Gaia Sequoia&lt;/em&gt; accretion events, respectively. The most metal-poor of these candidates have metallicities of  [Fe/H]=-3.31  and  [Fe/H]=-3.74 , respectively, helping to define the low-metallicity tail of the progenitors involved in the accretion events. We also find, consistent with other studies, that 21% of the sample have orbits that remain confined to within 3kpc of the Galactic plane, i.e., |Z&lt;em&gt;{max}|&amp;lt;=3 kpc. Of particular interest is a sub-sample (11% of the total) of low |Z&lt;/em&gt;{max}| stars with low eccentricities and prograde motions. The lowest metallicity of these stars has [Fe/H] = -4.30 and the sub-sample is best interpreted as the very low-metallicity tail of the metal-weak thick disk population. The low |Z&lt;em&gt;{max}|, low eccentricity stars with retrograde orbits are likely accreted, while the low |Z&lt;/em&gt;{max}|, high eccentricity pro- and retrograde stars are plausibly associated with the &lt;em&gt;Gaia Sausage&lt;/em&gt; system. We find that a small fraction of our sample (4% of the total) is likely escaping from the Galaxy, and postulate that these stars have gained energy from gravitational interactions that occur when infalling dwarf galaxies are tidally disrupted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mass loss along the red giant branch in 46 Globular Clusters and their multiple populations</title>
      <link>https://www.giacomocordoni.me/publication/paper16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.giacomocordoni.me/publication/paper16/</guid>
      <description>A chromosome map to unveil stellar populations with different magnesium abundances. The case of Omega Centauri</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gaia and Hubble unveil the kinematics of stellar populations in the Type II globular clusters Omega Centauri and M 22</title>
      <link>https://www.giacomocordoni.me/publication/paper14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.giacomocordoni.me/publication/paper14/</guid>
      <description>Internal dynamics of anomalous/type-II globular clusters combining Gaia astrometric information with HST proper motions</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A chromosome map to unveil stellar populations with different magnesium abundances. The case of Omega Centauri</title>
      <link>https://www.giacomocordoni.me/publication/paper15/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.giacomocordoni.me/publication/paper15/</guid>
      <description>A chromosome map to unveil stellar populations with different magnesium abundances. The case of Omega Centauri</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hubble Space Telescope UV Legacy Survey of Galactic globular clusters - XXI. Binaries among multiple stellar populations</title>
      <link>https://www.giacomocordoni.me/publication/paper13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.giacomocordoni.me/publication/paper13/</guid>
      <description>The Hubble Space Telescope UV Legacy Survey of Galactic globular clusters - XXI. Binaries among multiple stellar populations</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multiple populations in globular clusters and their parent galaxies</title>
      <link>https://www.giacomocordoni.me/publication/paper12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.giacomocordoni.me/publication/paper12/</guid>
      <description>By exploiting recent work based on Gaia, half of the known Type II GCs appear clustered in a distinct region of the integral of motions space, thus suggesting a common progenitor galaxy. Except for these Type II GCs, we do not find any significant difference in the MPs between clusters associated with different progenitors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three-component Kinematics of Multiple Stellar Populations in Globular Clusters with Gaia and VLT</title>
      <link>https://www.giacomocordoni.me/publication/paper11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.giacomocordoni.me/publication/paper11/</guid>
      <description>Analysis of the internal kinematics of multiple stellar populations in 7 galactic Globular clusters</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Role of Cluster Mass in the Multiple Populations of Galactic and Extragalactic Globular Clusters</title>
      <link>https://www.giacomocordoni.me/publication/paper9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.giacomocordoni.me/publication/paper9/</guid>
      <description>Similarly to Galactic GCs, the RGB width of Magellanic Cloud (MC) GCs correlates with cluster mass after removing the dependence from metallicity. This fact demonstrates that cluster mass is the main factor affecting the properties of MPs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chemical Abundances along the 1G Sequence of the Chromosome Maps: The Globular Cluster NGC 3201</title>
      <link>https://www.giacomocordoni.me/publication/paper10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.giacomocordoni.me/publication/paper10/</guid>
      <description>We suggest that a small variation in metals and binarity governs the color spread of the 1G in the ChM and that evolved BSs contribute to the bluest tail of the 1G sequence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Four stellar populations and extreme helium variation in the massive outer-halo globular cluster NGC 2419</title>
      <link>https://www.giacomocordoni.me/publication/paper8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.giacomocordoni.me/publication/paper8/</guid>
      <description>A new &lt;em&gt;economic&lt;/em&gt; combination of HST filter reveals the presence of four stellar populations with extreme Helium variations in the massive outer-halo globular cluster NGC2419.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A two orbits proposal to solve the age spread dilemma in young Magellanic Clouds clusters</title>
      <link>https://www.giacomocordoni.me/publication/paper4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.giacomocordoni.me/publication/paper4/</guid>
      <description>This is a two-orbits proposal to explore pre-main sequence (pre-MS) stars in Large Magellanic Cloud young clusters to assess, once and for all, if multiple bursts of star formation can be supported by these systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is helium the key parameter in the extended colour spread of the first generation stars in M3?</title>
      <link>https://www.giacomocordoni.me/publication/paper7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.giacomocordoni.me/publication/paper7/</guid>
      <description>Internal variation of helium content cannot reproduce all the observational constraints at the same time. The origin of the first generation colour spread is therefore still without a straightforward explanation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Four stellar populations and extreme helium variation in the massive outer-halo globular cluster NGC 2419</title>
      <link>https://www.giacomocordoni.me/nouse/paper4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.giacomocordoni.me/nouse/paper4/</guid>
      <description>The far-away massive cluster NGC2419 reveals interesting and extreme properties</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extended Main-sequence Turnoffs in the Double Cluster h and χ Persei: The Complex Role of Stellar Rotation</title>
      <link>https://www.giacomocordoni.me/publication/paper3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.giacomocordoni.me/publication/paper3/</guid>
      <description>By comparing the observations with simulated CMDs, we find that a simple population composed of coeval stars that span a wide range of rotation rates is unable to reproduce the color spread of the cluster’s MSs. We suggest that variable stars, binary interactions, and stellar rotation affect the eMSTO morphology of these very young.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hubble Space Telescope UV Legacy Survey of Galactic Globular Clusters. XIX. A Chemical Tagging of the Multiple Stellar Populations Over the Chromosome Maps</title>
      <link>https://www.giacomocordoni.me/publication/paper6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.giacomocordoni.me/publication/paper6/</guid>
      <description>Chemical Tagging of the Multiple Stellar Populations Over the Chromosome Maps</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mass Loss of Different Stellar Populations in Globular Clusters: The Case of M4</title>
      <link>https://www.giacomocordoni.me/publication/paper5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.giacomocordoni.me/publication/paper5/</guid>
      <description>New analysis of the HB branch reveals breaks the degeneracy on the horizontal branch. Second generation stars need to lose more mass than first generation stars</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extended main sequence turnoff as a common feature of galactic open clusters</title>
      <link>https://www.giacomocordoni.me/publication/paper2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.giacomocordoni.me/publication/paper2/</guid>
      <description>Photometric analysis of the extended Main Sequence Turn-off in 12 Galcactic Open clusters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hubble Space Telescope UV legacy survey of galactic globular clusters - XVI. The helium abundance of multiple populations</title>
      <link>https://www.giacomocordoni.me/publication/paper1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.giacomocordoni.me/publication/paper1/</guid>
      <description>Helium variations in multiple stellar populations for 58 galactic globular clusters</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extended main sequence turnoff as a common feature of galactic open clusters</title>
      <link>https://www.giacomocordoni.me/nouse/paper14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.giacomocordoni.me/nouse/paper14/</guid>
      <description>Photometric analysis of the extended Main Sequence Turn-off in 12 Galcactic Open clusters.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>