<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Da Costa G. S. on Giacomo Cordoni</title>
    <link>https://www.giacomocordoni.me/authors/da-costa-g.-s./</link>
    <description>Recent content in Da Costa G. S. on Giacomo Cordoni</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.giacomocordoni.me/authors/da-costa-g.-s./index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Galaxy&#39;s halo and very metal weak thick disk with SkyMapper and Gaia DR2</title>
      <link>https://www.giacomocordoni.me/publication/paper17/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.giacomocordoni.me/publication/paper17/</guid>
      <description>Galactic archeology with the dynamics of Extremely Metal-Poor stras from the &lt;em&gt;SkyMapper survey for Extremely Metal-Poor stars&lt;/em&gt;. and astrometry from Gaia DR2 to investigate the kinematics of a sample of 475 stars with a metallicity range of  -6.5&amp;lt;=[Fe/H]&amp;lt;=-2.05 dex. Exploiting the action map, we identify 16 and 40 stars dynamically consistent with the &lt;em&gt;Gaia Sausage&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Gaia Sequoia&lt;/em&gt; accretion events, respectively. The most metal-poor of these candidates have metallicities of  [Fe/H]=-3.31  and  [Fe/H]=-3.74 , respectively, helping to define the low-metallicity tail of the progenitors involved in the accretion events. We also find, consistent with other studies, that 21% of the sample have orbits that remain confined to within 3kpc of the Galactic plane, i.e., |Z&lt;em&gt;{max}|&amp;lt;=3 kpc. Of particular interest is a sub-sample (11% of the total) of low |Z&lt;/em&gt;{max}| stars with low eccentricities and prograde motions. The lowest metallicity of these stars has [Fe/H] = -4.30 and the sub-sample is best interpreted as the very low-metallicity tail of the metal-weak thick disk population. The low |Z&lt;em&gt;{max}|, low eccentricity stars with retrograde orbits are likely accreted, while the low |Z&lt;/em&gt;{max}|, high eccentricity pro- and retrograde stars are plausibly associated with the &lt;em&gt;Gaia Sausage&lt;/em&gt; system. We find that a small fraction of our sample (4% of the total) is likely escaping from the Galaxy, and postulate that these stars have gained energy from gravitational interactions that occur when infalling dwarf galaxies are tidally disrupted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gaia and Hubble unveil the kinematics of stellar populations in the Type II globular clusters Omega Centauri and M 22</title>
      <link>https://www.giacomocordoni.me/publication/paper14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.giacomocordoni.me/publication/paper14/</guid>
      <description>Internal dynamics of anomalous/type-II globular clusters combining Gaia astrometric information with HST proper motions</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multiple populations in globular clusters and their parent galaxies</title>
      <link>https://www.giacomocordoni.me/publication/paper12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.giacomocordoni.me/publication/paper12/</guid>
      <description>By exploiting recent work based on Gaia, half of the known Type II GCs appear clustered in a distinct region of the integral of motions space, thus suggesting a common progenitor galaxy. Except for these Type II GCs, we do not find any significant difference in the MPs between clusters associated with different progenitors.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>